# Tim Carlock

timothy.carlock@gmail.com



314.719.9051



New York, NY 10003



http://timcarlock.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tscarlock/



### Overview

I have over 15 years of engineering and product-development experience, with a particular interest in organizational design, product strategy and user experience. I have sector experience in financial services, consumer tech and business software. I cofounded a software startup where I managed product strategy and development, and I was an early(ish) employee at Uber.

## **Experience**

#### Engineering Manager, Eats - Restaurant Acquisition // Uber // San Francisco, CA

January 2019 - Present

- Leading a product-engineering group consisting of 16 engineers and one engineering manager split across three subteams: accounts platform, sales insights and self-signup (https://www.ubereats.com/restaurant/signup).
- Re-organized the engineering and product teams to increase development velocity, simplify project staffing and create new growth and development opportunities for engineers. Along with the Product Manager, I co-developed the team's revised vision, strategy, OKRs/KPIs and roadmap.
- · Established structure and processes for the team's projects, including a sprint-inspired process and pod-based approach to project staffing.
- Onboarded 11 engineers in the Toronto office and established an interim 6-month roadmap while their product organization was being built out.

#### Engineering Manager, Developer Experience // Uber // San Francisco, CA

March 2017 - January 2019

- Managed 11 engineers and tech leads across two sub-teams responsible for a portfolio of developer tools and automatedtesting services.
- · Worked with Product and Design to maintain a product roadmap, prioritize and plan projects and support an internal user base of 2,600 spread across 90 teams.
- Managed systems and initiatives to streamline manual testing and introduce an organization-wide platform for automated mobile and back-end testing.

#### Senior Engineer & Tech Lead, Shared Rides // Uber // San Francisco, CA

May 2016 - March 2017

- Technical leader for a team responsible for a variety of internal tools used to streamline and administer the Uber Pool product including mapping/pickup region management, test-trip automation, pricing experimentation and trip visualization.
- Formed and lead an internal community of web engineers focused on professional development and standards setting.

## Senior Engineer & Tech Lead, Uber for Business // Uber // San Francisco, CA

May 2014 - May 2016

- I led the team responsible for building and maintaining the business-facing dashboard of the U4B product.
- Worked closely with Product and Design and managed the prioritization, planning and implementation of a variety of key features including employee management, ride policies and billing.
- Led the effort to migrate the client application from BackboneJS to React and Redux.

#### Senior Engineer // Learnist // San Francisco, CA

Feb 2013 - May 2014

- I was a full-stack engineer and worked with Ruby on Rails and AngularJS, as well other technologies including CSS3, Sass, CoffeeScript, Redis and Rspec.
- Rebuilt the email-preference-management system including a redesign of the data-storage architecture, authorization and the UI for preference management.
- Rebuilt the content-curation UI and workflow, and created new designs for the primary application views.
- Managed a full migration from server-rendered views to a single page app built on AngularJS.

#### Software Engineer II // Expedia // San Francisco, CA

May 2012 - Feb 2013

- Developed an API to serve localized hotel reviews for multiple Expedia properties including search and travel packages. The API was developed using Java/Spring and MongoDB and was deployed to EC2.
- Managed deployment and provisioning using Jenkins, Capistrano and Chef.

#### Co-Founder & Product Lead // Nexly // San Francisco, CA

August 2009 - April 2012

Nexly was a lead-generation and tracking toolset for business-services companies. I was responsible for product strategy, design and development.

- Developed the application using Rails and PostgreSQL running on Heroku. Other technologies included CSS3, jQuery, CoffeeScript, Sass and HAML.
- Worked closely with users to understand key problems and needs, identify features and develop a product roadmap.
- Hired and managed designers and developers and oversaw all aspects of feature development, deployment and review.

#### Education

### University of Missouri - St Louis // Bachelor of Science - Information Systems

August 2004

• 3.91 Cumulative G.P.A.

#### University of Missouri - St Louis // Bachelor of Science - Finance

January 2003

- Student of the Pierre Laclede Honors College.
- President of the Delta Sigma Pi Business Fraternity.

#### **Skills**

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript/CoffeeScript, HTML/HAML, CSS/Sass, Java, C#, SQL

**Data Stores:** PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, MongoDB **Frameworks/Libraries:** React, Redux, Ruby on Rails

Toolset: Pivotal Tracker, Phabricator, Git, Jenkins, Sublime Text, Sketch